Ryan, when did the man first come on
your radar and maybe some of your first
impressions of of watching him?
>> Yeah. So, when we do our meetings, we go
um we take the average of like the high
grades uh from the fall and we work, you
know, from the top down. And when we
started the safety position, uh there's
a couple good ones that we liked.
Dylan's tape popped out like just the
sense of urgency that it plays with, the
speed. um we talk about taking the air,
you know, out of the defense or out of
the offense. His ability to close on the
football both in the run and the pass um
stood out really really quick. And as we
watched it, the comments you could hear,
I mean, this guy is obsessed with
football, plays fast, he's extremely
smart, u great leader, um violent in the
way that he plays the game, everything
that we're looking for. Then on top of
that, you have some versatility. Um if
he has to, he can go over and play a
little bit of nickel. Um he can play
free, he can play strong. So, uh, really
good fit for what we're trying to do.
>> How do you describe the aggressiveness
in his play style?
>> Oh, it's the aggressiveness. I mean, it
flies up the tape. He's a violent
football player. He strikes. Uh, there's
a knock back element to his tackling.
And, um, and again, just the speed.
There's like speed and there's like
violent speed in terms of just the
explosion off the spot. Um, and that's
what he brings and it's it's pretty easy
tape to watch. Yeah.
>> All right. What went into the weighing
hit Dylan's strengths versus some pretty
good candidates that were still there at
defensive tackle, defensive end?
>> Yeah. Um on our board again, you know,
we're talking about the board talking to
you. Um he was standing out. He was
elevated on the board um at a spot. So,
we kind of work lateral and see who else
is up there. Um and he was the number
one in our priority list. Um, we take
the board before obviously all this
kicks off when we sequence it and he was
the top sequence guy on our on our on
our board.
>> Were there any anxious moments as he
kind of had the board going? He was
clearly your guy like J said the board
was wide open. Was it getting anxious as
you get closer and closer? Yeah, it it
was um I think I talked about our
simulator uses some mock um hundreds of
mocks uh to kind of hone in and give us
different challenges as we're picking to
go through and simulate the draft. Um it
was 50/50 with him oftent times.
So we weren't sure if he was going to
make it. I think there was a lot I think
it was 18 seemed to be the spot that
everyone said he was going to. We knew
that if he got past that there's a good
chance. Um, again, we in our sequence,
we had probably two more guys that were
were close. Um, so we knew that we were
going to get a good football player.
They were all I drew a line on our top
100 of ones that we would be looking to
trade back, trade up and um, it fell
where we had a couple guys there in the
sequence. So, we looked to potentially
move back a little bit. There wasn't
much interest right behind us where we
felt comfortable in terms of the
numbers. Um, so we just moved forward
and we we love the player, so we we were
excited about pressure is there in a
situation where you need a day one
starter to go in and then be able to
land that guy, but just like the process
of getting him, how do you feel in that?
And what is it like as you start to see
the way the board falls before you guys
get on the clock?
>> Yeah. Um, you try to stay true to
the top guys on the board. Um, you know,
there there's a couple situations where
potentially could be in a position where
we have starters, but we would have very
similar to last year, right, with with
Cole and Coulson. Um, it just happened
for this one that the sequence landed
right on a a need. Um, so he's going to
have the ability to come in and compete
for a starting role and obviously that's
that's going to be an open spot. Um,
where those guys are going to compete
and the tape tells us he's going to have
a really good opportunity to do that. Um
but this was a really cool opportunity
where again a need and best player
available um fell the way that we needed
it to
>> this offseason you and Ben both talked
about the need to get better
>> um from the outside is there still a way
to do that in your mind on day two of
the draft and if you don't you just have
to the guys in house
>> yeah I think both of those things are
true I think there's some opportunity of
guys uh on the board still um and then
absolutely just what these guys are
working on this week uh was for that
group to continue to get better so they
can be more effective. Um I know the
coaches spent a lot of time in the
offseason detailing where uh spots where
they feel like we can get better, maybe
some tweaks in what we're doing um the
way we're coaching things. Um and then
naturally just a second year in the
system, you would think that some of
these guys would continue to get better
and elevate their game. And then if you
if you help the secondary, like you
know, they're related to a degree.
Obviously, uh the Dline helps uh the
back end more often than not. Uh but in
a situation where, you know, we have
good corners, good safeties, uh we can
be in a position where maybe we can have
the quarterback hold the ball a little
longer.
>> Did the edge rushers kind of break the
way you thought they would?
>> Yeah. Considering the the combination of
of Kobe and Dylan and the speed you
added back there, what does what strikes
you about you do with those two guys and
how fast they are?
>> Yeah, I think you just match up better.
Um, you eliminate, you know, every time
we especially like our pro staff when we
do an advance on our opponent. We're
looking for targets, looking for guys
that we can find mismatches on and
expose. So, when you have speed and you
have a lot of guys that can cover in
different spots, um your ability to hang
in there, cover longer while you're
bringing pressure, uh things like that
enhances the entire defense.
>> Mentioned with the combination of Kobe
and Dylan that there's no weaknesses
between the two of them because they can
do everything. What does that do for a
defense when you're secondary? I mean,
that would just point to the secondary
being the strength of this defense. What
can that do in year two with Dennis
having that?
>> Yeah, that group can elevate. Obviously,
there's a lot of turnovers. um you can
increase that number which is going to
be you know a big challenge for those
guys but I think just like I said taking
the air out uh anytime we've seen a
defense and you feel like like it's
suffocating uh because of the speed um
that's what we're trying to do
>> right he he goes from Purdue to Oregon
where did you see the most development
like why does he really take off once
that changes made
>> yeah um you know there's plenty I mean
you can mature
uh continue to grow in just your
understanding of the game. Um getting
bigger, stronger, faster, different
schemes, coaches. So, there's a lot of
things that could potentially go into
that. Um you know, he his first year as
a freshman, I think he had six
interceptions and was really really
active, too. Um so, when we worked
through all of his tape, there's a lot
of things that popped up from the time
he his first year to his last year.
>> Brad talked about the football
character. How did that jump out to you
throughout the process of getting to
know him? Yeah, it's off the charts and
we we have so many good sources in terms
of um guys that he's played with and
that that's all the way from Westfield
High School all the way to Oregon and
the feedback that we got was incredible.
Um I think um one of our guys probably
Brett came down to talk to you and I
don't know if he mentioned it but you
know we had talked about this as a very
similar type person player combination
to what Coulson was. Um the work ethic
um again that passion for ball was off
the charts. We grade on a scale 1 to
nine. Um there's no fives and there's no
twos. Uh cuz I don't want there's no
fence grades. U there's a lot of sevens
and eights when you look across this
guy's character. So u really happy with
the type of person we're bringing in. Is
it the combo of football character and
kind of the speed that that makes you
feel good about a safety in round one
where there aren't a lot of them that go
in round one and you can often times
find pretty good ones a little bit later
on in the draft when you think about
positional value.
>> Yeah, you got to look at versatility. So
if it's a safety and it's like kind of
old school box safety um that maybe
doesn't have a lot of coverage um you
know value probably stays down just a
little bit. So that's why we felt
comfortable taking Dylan where he was.
There's versatility. So there's multiple
positions he can play on top of the
ability to cover the range helping in
the pass game third down. Um and then
when you have you got Kyler, you got
Kobe, you got guys that you can do a lot
of different things to confuse the
defense. Um that was kind of on the
checklist of a safety taking in one and
grading them where we had him graded.
>> Ryan Ben has complimented safeties in
the past like during the season. like
what was his reaction? What was his
input? I thought
>> Yeah, he was he was fired up. Um we
spent time together. He would come in
watch watch tape with with our group and
this was one of the guys that we had on
when he was in and I mean we both I can
now feel Ben like he doesn't have to say
anything. I can feel his like body
language start to like get excited about
somebody and you could you could feel
it. Um because again it's that style of
play that he he he has that like I said
it's contagious. It's It's the type of
um player that we want on our football
team.
>> Is there anything that surprised you
from the first round tonight?
>> Um yeah, but I'm not going to get into
other people's picks.
>> Walk off pick at Penn State as a
signature play. What struck you about
just the the moment and the actual play
that he made in?
>> Yeah, we we want players that can rise
to the level. Um we plan on playing a
lot of big games moving forward. We're
going to I don't know what the schedule
is going to be, but I'm sure there's
going to be a lot of prime time games.
There's going to be um hopefully we're
back and deep into the playoffs. So, we
need guys that thrive in those moments.
Uh so, when you show those things, um we
feel even better about you.
>> When you look at your board heading into
tomorrow and the three picks that you
have, how do you feel about your needs
and and the way things kind of shift
out?
>> Yeah. Uh a lot of good options. A lot of
good options. Um, I'll say this, this
was probably the most aggressive we were
in terms of the guys that we really
like. Like, they have to play our style.
Um, they got to have the right makeup.
Um, in terms of our scheme fits, like
all of that had to be there. If it
wasn't there, you're off the board. Um,
we were really aggressive with it. So,
when you look at it, it feels really
thin. Um, but that's a good thing. I
think it's a really good thing because
we're very selective of who we want. Um
there's some historical numbers that I
have that makes me feel confident that
um there's going to be guys that we like
still available to us. So thankfully the
numbers are high enough where you know
I'll be able to sleep a little bit
tonight. So
>> what put you guys in that what put you
guys in that space to be more
aggressive? Is it the clear vision from
the coaching staff? Is it the process
the point you are in the process of
roster building?
>> I would say both. Both um just confident
confidence in our system. Um, and then
again, this staff is unbelievable. We're
just giving clarity. And I think as as
we continue to work with each other,
we're going to know exactly what we're
looking for. Um, so why why mess around
with, you know, those that don't fit
what we're trying to do and then we're,
you know, then we're having
conversations in, you know, the
summertime and in the fall of why that
guy can't play for us or, you know, it's
not a fit. So, um, yeah, I think both
things are true. just confidence in the
system. Our scouts do unbelievable job
gathering information and then our staff
is our coaching staff is really clear
with what they're looking for. So, it's
a really good marriage.
>> I know these guys are are kind of
versatile, but do you see Kobe as
strength at free and and feeling and
strong or need to do a lot of matching
based on coverages? Well, I think now,
and that's probably a better question
for DA, but I'm sure depending on who
we're going against, um, he can do
different things. Probably makes
everything look the same, but do
different things out of it. Um, which as
offense is is difficult to prepare for.
>> Awesome. Thank you. Thank you all.